Guide to the Walter Stainton papers, 1914-1983
Stainton, Walter papers, 1914-1983
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Walter Stainton papers, 1914-1983
14-24-573
Stainton
14.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, printed materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Professional papers, and records of the Cornell Dramatic Club; also student scrapbook.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Walter Stainton graduated from Cornell in the Class of 1920 and later returned as a professor of Speech and Drama. He was heavily involved on campus in the ROTC program and Cornell WEAI radio station but poured most of his resources into Cornell University Theatre. He eventually inherited the role of director from A.M. Drummond and was often consulted for assistance by other institutions with theatre construction and performance inquires. Stainton also led the university's film program and was deeply involved with the showing of new and classic films on campus. He was a member of multiple theatre and film organizations, including the Society for Cinema Studies and the National Board of Review of Motion Pictures. Stainton also focused specifically in his own work on Ithaca's past film industry and the history of film and theatre in Upstate New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Scrapbook for 1916-1921 when Cornell undergraduate. Several documents and publications with scientific focus, specifically physics. Professional papers and correspondence concerning coursework in the Speech and Drama department and Cornell University Theatre. Scripts and statistical documents for Cornell Dramatic Club and Cornell Summer Theatre. Assorted papers concerning Cornell University ROTC, Cornell WEAI radio station, and other undergraduate organizations. Professional documents and correspondence addressing Ithaca and upstate New York area, focusing on theatre companies and performances. Technical and commercial publications, journal articles, and newspaper articles concerning theatre and film accomplishments, updates, and pop culture. International and national playbills and brochures for various theatre performances.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Stainton, Walter.; Cornell Dramatic Club; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University.Class of 1920.
Subjects:
Theater--Study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Speeches by W.H. Stainton
Series II. Contributions to Articles, Publications, and Presentations
Articles
Presentations/Conferences
Reviews
Miscellaneous
Series III. Theatre Information
Lyceum Theatre
Strand Theatre
Other Theatres in Ithaca
Other Theatres in United States
Theatre Genres
Series IV. Theatre Productions
National Playbills and Programs
International Playbills and Programs
Series V. Theatre Construction
Lighting Catalogs
Lighting Articles
Lighting Notes
Technical Catalogs and Pamphlets
Construction and Design Articles
Acoustics and Sound Articles
Technical Photos
Series VI. Cornell University Campus
General Campus
Willard Straight Hall/Theatre
Statler Hall
Series VII. Cornell Dramatic Club
Books and Documents from Past Plays
Playbills
Administration Documents
Financial Documents
Correspondence
CDC 50th Anniversary
Performance Photos
Miscellaneous
Series VIII. Other Cornell University Undergraduate Fields and Organizations
Cornell WEAI Radio Station
Cornell Productions and Concerts
Cornell R.O.T.C.
Cornell Summer Theatre
Cornell University Theatre
Cornell University Alumni
Cornell Cinema
Cornell Greek Life
Summer Ithaca
Series IX. W. H. Stainton Personal and Professional Documents
Undergraduate Documents
Course Related Documents
Student Papers and Research
Scheduling and Faculty Related Documents
Graduate Students
Assorted Notes
Assorted Correspondence
Society for Cinema Studies
Miscellaneous
Series X. Ithaca and Upstate New York
Dewitt Historical Society
Series XI. Assorted Newspaper and Magazine Articles
Film Articles
Theatre Articles
Series XII. Assorted Publications
Series XIII. Miscellaneous
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Speeches by W.H. Stainton
  - Camp Cory Orientation, 1964, September 16, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cornell Library Associates: Statler Ballroom, 1965, June 17, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Class of 1937 Reunion, 1967, June 17, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Talk on Lighting at Elmira Little Theatre, 1949, December 12, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Talk on Stage Lighting for N.Y. State Community Theatre Conference, 1950, October 15, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "The Passing of the Old Advanced," 1912, June 28, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Problems of Stage Lighting, N.A.T.S. Chicago, 1930, December 31, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Presentation Before Cortland Community Players on "Production Problems," 1938, October 6, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Stainton's Address to Class of 1937 Woman, June 1967, June 17, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Series II. Contributions to Articles, Publications, and Presentations
  - Articles
    - Movie Pre-History: "Films in Review," June-July 1965, June-July 1965 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - "Measurements of Natural Light During the Solar Eclipse: January 25, 1925; Presented: 1925, April 9, 1925; This also includes Stainton's notes. The article was presented to the Illuminating Engineering Society on April 9, 1925. (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - "Report of the director of the Players to the Council of Student Organizations for the Year, 1927-1928, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - "Preliminary Check on 'Arena' Site for Second Term," 1950-1951, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - "The Phenomenon of Broca and Sulzer in Foveal Vision," from Journal of the Optical Society of America and Review of Scientific Instruments, Vol. 16, No. 1, January 1928, January 1928 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "Some Characteristics of Modern Stage Lighting," from Sibley Journal of Engineering, Vol. 42 #6, 1928, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - "Some Notes on Photography for the Non-Professional Stage," 1941, January 1, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - "Color Music," 1942, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "Phonemic Microtimy," 1942, June 19, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - "Use of Training Films, and Motion Picture Equipment," 1942, August 3, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - "Criticism on Proposed Layout for Photo Science Service in Rand Hall," 1946, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - "What We Have Been Trying to Do in the Theatre," 1950, November-December, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - "Pearl White in Ithaca," Published in "Films in Review", 1951, May 1951; Also contains correspondence concerning the article. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - "Theatre Buildings-And What You Can Do About Them," Presented at N.Y. State Community Theatre Conference, 1951, October 20, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Players Magazine with Stainton's Article "Take a Good Luck at Lighting," 1952, January 1952 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - "Theatre Buildings and What Can be Done," for Players Magazine, 1952, May 1952 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Films in Review: "A 60-Year Calendar of Motion Pictures", August-September, 1952; Also contains mentions of the article in various other publications. (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Original Text of "Stage Lighting" and Edited Version Printed in Players Magazine, 1953, February 1953 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - "The Theatre" - Papers Presented at the Eighth Ann Arbor Conference, 1950, April 1950 (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence and Drafting of Article on Cinema Chronology for "Films in Review," 1964-1965, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - "Hollywood-on-Cayuga," by Walter Stainton for "Films in Review," May 1957, May 1957 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Page from Cornell Alumni News, September 1965, September 1965; Mentions Stainton's new article on "Movie Prehistory" in "Films in Review." (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence and Drafts for "Films in Review" Articles, 1965, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - "Some Characteristics of Modern Stage Lighting," by Walter S. Stainton (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Article on the Style of Motion Pictures (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - List of Articles by Walter H. Stainton, April 1941-March 1942, April 1941-March 1942 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - "Color Music," by Walter H. Stainton (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Presentations/Conferences
    - Programs, etc. From Ann Arbor Conference, 1950, April 14-15, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Documents for Debate on "Censorship of Motion Pictures," 1956, March 14, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Documents About Talk to Society of Photographic Scientists and Engineers, Ithaca Chapter: 1958, March 1958 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Program for American Physical Society/Optical Society of America NY Meeting, With Stainton's Presentation on Foveal Vision, 1927, February 25-26, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "Special Lighting Programs," N.A.T.S. and N.T.C. Meeting in NY, 1933, December 28, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - "Technical Production Problems," N.A.T.S. and N.T.C. Meeting in Chicago, 1935, December 1935 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "Stage Lighting - Some Errors in the Books," from Eastern Pub. Sp. Conference in NY, April 18, 36, April 18, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - "Recording the Production," from Washington Meeting, 1941, January 1, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "Little Theatre Conference," for N.T.C., 1941, May 25, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Presentation of "Lighting-Elmira Little Theatre," 1949, December 12, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - "Multi-Purpose Theatre" - Presented at Eighth Ann Arbor conference, April 14-15, 1950, April 14-15, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Presentation on Lighting at N.Y.S. Community Theatre Conference, 1950, October 15, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - "Multi-Purpose Theatre" - Presented at Eighth Ann Arbor conference, April 14-15, 1950, April 14-15, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Presentation to Torch Club on "Movie Censorship," 1956, December 12, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Notes and Presentation on Theatre Design to Architecture Students, July 5, 1957, July 5, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Reviews
    - Archaeology of the Cinema Review: Films in Review (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Review of Irene Mawer's "The Art of Mime: Its History and Technique in Education and the Theatre," 1933, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Review of C. Harold Ridge's "Stage Lighting," 1935, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Review of "Scenery for the Theatre," 1938, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - "Films in Review," With Stainton's Review of "Theatre Arts Anthology,, a Record and a Prophecy," 1951, February 1951 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Review of" Three British Film Plays: Brief Encounter, Odd Man Out, Scott of the Antartic," 1951, August 22, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Review of Buchanan's "The Film in Education," October 1952, October 1952 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Review by Stainton of "The Film of Murder in the Cathedral," 1952, October 15, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Review for "Stage Scenery and Lighting" (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Review for "Designing for the Stage," by Doris Zinkelsen (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Review of "Modern Theatre Practice - A Handbook for Non-Professionals" (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Review of "A Method of Lighting the Stage" (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous
    - "Films in Review" Papers and "Le Prince," 1962-1963, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Ithaca Journal" 150-Year Special Issue, May 1965, May 1965 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "Hollywood Quarterly" "Hollywood-on-Cayuga," Letter from June 8, 1951, June 8, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - "Enter Hamlet" and Stainton's Response, March 1979, March 1979; Includes mention of Alexander Drummond/=. (Box 12, Folder 76)
    - Introductions for Presentations by Arthur Knight, Stanley Vanderbeek, and Donald Mitchell Oenslager (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - "Presented at Beano," May 14, 1948, May 14, 1948; Short play with Cornell-related aspects and themes. (Box 8, Folder 49)
- Series III. Theatre Information
  - Lyceum Theatre
    - Letters Concerning Investigation of Lyceum Theatre, 1941-1971, 1941-1971 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - DeWitt Historical Society Presentation on Lyceum Theatre, November 29, 1961, November 29, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Letters Regarding Publication of Articles on Lyceum Theatre, 1962, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence Concerning Lyceum Theatre, 1941-1964, 1941-1964 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper Clippings About Lyceum Theatre, 1942-1964, 1941-1961 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Notes on Lyceum Theatre (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Ithaca "50 Years Ago" Clippings Concerning Lyceum, Pub. 1943-1958, 1943-1958 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Ithaca "50 Years Ago" Clippings Concerning Lyceum, Pub. 1959-1974, 1959-1974 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Ithaca "25 Years Ago" Clippings Concerning Lyceum, Pub. 1948-1958, 1948-1958 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Ithaca "20 Years Ago" Clipping Concerning Lyceum, Pub. 1953, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Ithaca "35 Years Ago" Clipping Concerning Lyceum, Pub. 1953, February 1953 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Newspaper Articles Related to Lyceum Theatre, 1976-1977, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Photos and Newspaper Prints of Lyceum Theatre (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Specs of Lyceum Theatre (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Assorted Paperwork and Playbills for Lyceum Theatre, 1914-1925, 1914-1925 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Various Photos of Lyceum Theatre, Including Detailed Interior (Copies Dated: March 3, 1942) (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Strand Theatre
    - Youth Grand Project with Glen Becker, 1978, April-May 1978 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Strand Theatre Membership Committee Letters, 1978-1979, April 1978-August 1979 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Newspaper Articles Concerning 1981 Fire at Strand Theatre, March 13-14, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Ithaca "25 Years Ago" Clippings Concerning Strand Theatre, 1941-1966, 1941-1966 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Ithaca "50 Years Ago" Clippings Concerning Strand Theatre, 1956-1958, 1956-1958 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Newspaper Articles About Strand Theatre, 1977, June-October 1977 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Newspaper Articles About Strand Theatre, 1983, January-September 1983 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Playbills for Strand Theatre, 1932-1950, 1932-1950 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Strand Theatre Membership Committee Letters, 1977, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Invitations, Pamphlets, and Show Flyers from Strand, 1977-1979, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Undated Misc. Strand Newsletters (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Personal Notes on History of Strand Theatre (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Playbills from the Strand Theatre (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Other Theatres in Ithaca
    - Articles and Notes on Crescent Theatre, 1918-1971, 1918-1971 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Ithaca "25 Years Ago" Article About Star Theatre, Pub. 1954, July 2, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Newspaper Articles on Happy Hour Theatre, 1960-1965, 1960-1965; Also contains a 1914 Playbill. (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Ithaca "50 Years Ago" Articles About Star Theatre, Pub. 1961-1974, 1961-1974 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Ithaca "50 Years Ago" Articles on Ithaca Theatres, Pub. 1956-1967, 1956-1967; Also contains related articles from 1976. (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Articles on Star Theatre, 1965/Undated Star Playbill, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Ithaca "50 Years Ago" Article on Billiken Theatre, Pub. 1973, April 14,1973 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Newspaper Articles About Closing of Temple Theatre, 1976, August 1976 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Newspaper Articles About State Theatre, 1976-1979, July 1976-May 1979 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Assorted Newspaper Articles (1941-1964) and Photos (1942) of Wilgus Opera House, 1941-1964 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Assorted Notes on Ithaca Theatres (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Reports and Schematics for Ithaca Arts Center, Includes an undated map of Ithaca. (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Other Theatres in United States
    - Skaneateles Summer Theatre Season Calendar, 1948, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Newspaper Articles about the Metropolitan Opera House, December 23, 1934, December 23, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Floor Plan of Stage in Grand Ballroom of Waldorf Astoria, New York, February 1, 1936, February 1, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Articles on Specific Theater Models (Some with Pictures/Schematics), 1940-1967, 1940-1967; Includes: Natural Theater in Red Rocks Park, Denver, Colorado; Lincoln Center; Radio City Music Hall; Workshop Theater at Bennington College; La Jolla's Hourglass Stage in California. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Articles about Radio City Musical Hall (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Booklets on History of Koch Memorial Theatre at University of North Carolina (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Souvenir Program for "Family Portrait" at Portland Civic Theatre Week, February 1941, February 1941 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - News and Printed Material on Several Theatres, Includes information about: First Theatre of California, Phoenix Little Theatre, New Repertory Theatre, and Kenneth Sawyer Goodman Memorial Theatre. (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Berkeley High School Community Theatre: Correspondence and Photos (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - "A New Civil Theatre for Jamestown" (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - "Specifications for Stage Equipment, Tracks, Rigging Electric Equipment, and Stage Switchboard for Albert Taylor Hall" (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - "Recommended Mounting Locations for Proposed Stage Lighting Equipment for Albert Taylor Hall," January 22, 1947", January 22, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Notes and Newspaper Articles on Modern and Upcoming Education Theaters and Buildings, 1950-1956 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Assorted Articles on Theatres, Includes: Rockefeller Center and Denver's Theatre of the Red Rocks. (Box 5, Folder 85)
      - Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts
        - The Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts Bulletins/Advertisements, 1940-1946, 1940-1946 (Box 1, Folder 30)
        - Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts Brochures and Invitations, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 50)
        - Correspondence and Notes Concerning Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts, June-December 1940, June-December 1940 (Box 5, Folder 51)
        - "The Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts Quarterly Bulletin," 1940-1942, 1940-1942 (Box 5, Folder 52)
        - Tickets for The Children's Theater of Syracuse: "Let's Make Believe Again," April 18-19, 1941, April 18-19, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 53)
        - Syracuse Museum of Fine Art Stage Plans (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Theatre Genres
    - George Kin Leung: On Chinese Theatre, 1938, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Russian Theatre and Meyerhold, 1932-1951, 1932-1951 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - French Theatre: Articles and Papers, 1935-1960, 1935-1960 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Expressionism Papers, 1936-1953, 1936-1953 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Irish Theatre: Notes and Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Georg Fuchs: Papers and Articles (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - German Theatre and Irwin Piscator: Articles (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Impressionism Paper by Barbara Larson (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Harley Granville-Barker: Bibliographies, Information about important figure for English Theatre. (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Independent Theatre Movement in England (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Papers on Leopold Jessner and German Stage (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Japanese Theatre (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Notes and Papers About German Theatre (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Notes on British Theatre (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - "The Theatre in Israel," Florence L. Gorman, 1953, May 12, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 74)
    - Articles on German Films, Especially "The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari" and "The Last Laugh" (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - Paper on British Film Industry (Box 10, Folder 95)
    - Glossaries of Theatre Terms (Box 11, Folder 76)
    - "Theatre in France" (Box 11, Folder 77)
- Series IV. Theatre Productions
  - National Playbills and Programs
    - Playbills and Notes for First Annual Drama Festival of the N.Y. State Name Schools, 1938, April 28-30, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Playbills for University of Oregon's "The Playbill of the Western World," 1947, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Newsletter and Playbills for Elmire Little Theatre, 1947-1949, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Playbill for Brown University's "The Country Wife," 1949, May 1949 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Playbill and Article for Ithaca Commmunity, 1954, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Program for "The Miracle," 1924, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Playbills for Henry Miller's Theatre, 1925, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Playbills for Ziegfeld Thatre, 1925/1929, 1925/1929; Special attention is paid here to Billie Burke. (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Playbills for Various N.Y. Theatres, 1925-1933, 1925-1933 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Playbills for the Guild Theatre, 1925/1933, 1925/1933 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Program for "The Miracle," 1924, 1926-1968 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Playbills for Charles Hopkins Theater and Productions, 1927, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Playbill and Libretto for Metropolitan Opera House, "The Flying Dutchman," December 1930, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Professional Playbills, 1937, 1937; Includes: "Of Mice and Men," "I Married an Angel," "The Golden Boy," "Susan and God," "The Women Have Their Way," and 'Twelfth Night." (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Playbills for N.Y. College/University Productions, 1950-1968, 1950-1968 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Playbill for "J.B." with Christopher Plummer and Basil Rathbone, December 1958, December 1958 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Playbills from N.Y. Phoenix Theatre (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Playbills from Century Theatre's "Danton's Tod" (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Assorted American Theatre Playbills (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Playbill from Pennsylvania Intercollegiate Dramatic Association's Sixth Annual Dramatic Contest, 1931, April 17-18, 1931; Also has Stainton's notes about the performance. (Box 7, Folder 96)
    - Playbill for Richard Burton's "Hamlet," 1965, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - One Act Play Programs (Box 10, Folder 99)
    - New York City Theatre Playbills, 1952-1966, 1952-1966 (Box 11, Folder 78)
    - Assorted Brochures and Programs, 1950s, 1950s (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Playbill for Purdue Playshop's "Caesar and Cleopatra," May 1958, May 1958 (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Orpheum Theatre Programs, Jersey City, December 1915-December 1918, December 27, 1915-December 30, 1918 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Playbills for Other Jersey City Theatres, 1917-1921, 1917-1921 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Orpheum Theatre Programs, Jersey City, January 6, 1919-May 7, 1923, January 6, 1919-May 7, 1923 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Playbills from the National Theatre in Jersey City, Early 1920s, Early 1920s (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Playbills for Other American Theatres, 1920s, 1920s (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - American Playbills, 1928, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - American Playbills, 1932, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - "Five Seasons of Balboa Little Theatre," October 1934-June 1939, October 1934-June 1939 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - "The Playbill,: Belasco Theatre, 1935, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - American Playbills, 1936, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - "The Living Newspaper" from the Adelphi Theatre, January 1938, January 17, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - American Playbills, 1939, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - American Playbills, 1940, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Playbill for "Ladies in Retirement" at Barnstormers Theatre, August 1942, August 1942 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - American Playbills, 1943, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Assorted American Playbills, 1946, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Ithaca College Theatre Playbill for "Skylark," 1947, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - American Playbills, 1950, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Assorted American Playbills, 1952-1954, 1952-1954 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - International Playbills and Programs
    - Playbills from French Theatres, 1910/1961, 1910/1961 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Paris Theatre Programs, 1948-1950, 1948-1950 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - French Theatre Programs (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Playbills from Royal Opera House, 1955, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 24)